<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.processimagining.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.processimagining.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2023-08-12T03:37:51+00:00</updated><id>https://www.processimagining.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Process Imagining</title><subtitle>Thoughts on religion and philosophy in process and post-structural perspective.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">spaces and the imagination</title><link href="https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2023/spaces-and-the-imagination/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="spaces and the imagination" /><published>2023-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2023/spaces-and-the-imagination</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2023/spaces-and-the-imagination/"><![CDATA[<p>quote about imagination lost because we do not have a chance to break out of space, or to find space</p>

<p>space in bachelard
focus on space. uses a home to explain the depths of the mind.  in order to reflect upon it, the home is covered, a deleuzian veil so that the metaphorical, the imaginative or the imaginary can come into focus. It moves one beyond the actual to the possible. the use of stairs, the attic, the rooms, the basement, all play a part.</p>

<p>space in whitehead
Space in whitehead functions a bit different.  both context and distance play a part in the process of space.  time is also included.  the imagination, the imaginary, or creativity, takes into account a multitude of factors to come towards a satisfaction (satisfaction as a culminating moment in the act of becoming).</p>

<p>space in corbin?
corbin space and the performative, where action takes place, where understanding becomes.  we are invited to be a part of the play, the drama that unfolds.</p>

<p>why important
to be bound by a context forces creativity to come into action, to make best what can be done.  Most of ones understanding of the imagination is from those who are held in certain contexts, whether benefitting from academia, wealth, etc.  Imagination is limited by the context one exists in.  thus the type of house one had growing up is the context by which our imaginative becoming derives.  But does the limitation of space also predetermine or limit what one can understand? Or are the values that are unfolded within the context the limiting factor? moved by whitehead about the stranger and the opening of adventure.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="imagination" /><category term="space" /><category term="philosophy" /><category term="alfred-north-whitehead" /><category term="gaston-bachelard" /><category term="imagination" /><category term="space" /><category term="context" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[understanding imagination, space and context in Gaston Bachelard and Alfred North Whitehead]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">quote, michael v. mcginnis, rewilding imagination</title><link href="https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2023/quote-michael-v_kmt90aryyik6wvkc/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="quote, michael v. mcginnis, rewilding imagination" /><published>2023-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2023/quote-michael-v_kmt90aryyik6wvkc</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2023/quote-michael-v_kmt90aryyik6wvkc/"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>The problem is that industrial culture is based on a mode of mimesis that simulates itself over and over again. In our emerging global society, the human being stands in the middle of a “fun zone” with walls of mirrors, where one’s reflection is all-too- human. Something is behind these human images-a psychology that supports a mimesis that fails to recognize its origin, and, therefore, it downplays the sensuous life.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>#imagination</p>

<p>#creativeimagination</p>

<p>#induastrialsociety</p>

<p>#culture</p>

<p>#machinations</p>

<p>#sustainability</p>

<p>#nature</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="imagination" /><category term="creativeimagination" /><category term="induastrialsociety" /><category term="culture" /><category term="machinations" /><category term="sustainability" /><category term="nature" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[quote on the imagination]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">goethe and the imagination</title><link href="https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2023/goethe-and-the-imagination_92q4bxj6xnw9o6r0/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="goethe and the imagination" /><published>2023-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2023/goethe-and-the-imagination_92q4bxj6xnw9o6r0</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2023/goethe-and-the-imagination_92q4bxj6xnw9o6r0/"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>“A man born and bred up to the so-called exact sciences does not find it easy to realize, perched as he is on the heights of his own rationality, that there might also exist an exactitude of the imagination working through the senses, without which art would be simply unthinkable” (Aphorismen und Fragmente, Werke, Zürich, 1952, 17, 779)</p>
</blockquote>

<p>#goethe</p>

<p>#imagination</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="imagination" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[quote on the imagination]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">hakim bey and the imagination</title><link href="https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2022/hakim-bey-immediatism-8-9_aqwpjv3dnjjjoyal/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="hakim bey and the imagination" /><published>2022-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2022/hakim-bey-immediatism-8-9_aqwpjv3dnjjjoyal</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2022/hakim-bey-immediatism-8-9_aqwpjv3dnjjjoyal/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="hakim-bey-immediatism-8-9">hakim bey, immediatism, 8-9.</h1>

<blockquote>
  <p>Computers, video, radio, printing presses, synthesizers, fax machines, tape recorders, photocopiers - these things make good toys, but terrible addictions.</p>

  <p>Finally we realize we cannot “reach out &amp; touch someone” who is not present in the flesh. These media may be useful to our art - but they must not possess us, nor must they stand between, mediate, or separate us from our animal/animate selves. We want to control our media, not be controlled by them. And we should like to remember a certain psychic martial art which stresses  the realization that the body itself is the least mediated of all media.</p>
</blockquote>

<h1 id="hakim-bey-immediatism-7">hakim bey, immediatism, 7.</h1>

<blockquote>
  <p>For art, the intervention of Capital always signals a further degree of mediation. To say that art is commodified is to say that a mediation, or standing-inbetween, has occurred, &amp; that this betweenness  amounts to a split, &amp; that this split amounts to “alienation.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>#art</p>

<p>#creation</p>

<p>#imagination</p>

<p>#hakimbey</p>

<p>#technology</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="imagination" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[quote on the imagination]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">a quote a friend gave me</title><link href="https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2022/a-quote-a-friend-gave-me/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a quote a friend gave me" /><published>2022-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2022/a-quote-a-friend-gave-me</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2022/a-quote-a-friend-gave-me/"><![CDATA[<p>This quote was given to me by a friend, as I was passing through (and still am) going through a difficult transition.  The reality is, this quote hurts. It bothers me. But at the same time, it is very process oriented, and therefore I return to it. I argue with it, but it remains.  Here is the quote:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>To live is to die a thousand deaths to the person I used to be. I die when I accept that I will never be the person I wanted to grow up to be. My task, however, is just to travel between each version of myself and honor what emerges along the way.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>May your journey, in whatever phase it is in, may it be forgiving, may it be stretching, and may you find the joyful moments within them.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="life" /><category term="thestruggle" /><category term="notwhatIwanted" /><category term="apartoflife" /><category term="makethemost" /><category term="learntochange" /><category term="imagine" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[a quote a friend gave me]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">reflection on thinking that is reactionary</title><link href="https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2021/thinking-that-is-reactionary-always-comes-at-a-cost/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="reflection on thinking that is reactionary" /><published>2021-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2021/thinking-that-is-reactionary-always-comes-at-a-cost</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2021/thinking-that-is-reactionary-always-comes-at-a-cost/"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>Thinking that is reactionary always comes at a cost. It starts with an act of rejection, yet more often than not it remains committed to the logical framework that it apparently rejects.
~ Sepper, <em>Understanding Imagination</em>, 3.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I have been reflecting on this particular piece as it puts into words a dillemma I have had for quite some time.  Whenever we engage the other with a set of tools, let us use the tools of logic, it is assumed that logic is universal.  When one does not follow the same logic as others do, we enter into the idea that they are less cultured, primitive, barbaric, as they are not using the same logic we are, especially if we are trained.  At that brings concern.  Logic is as varied, or produces as varied results as the imagination may produce, since it follows a criteria, and criteria is vairable as well.  Only when we start universalizing the criteria do we see uniformity.  But that is just as dangerous!  In uniformity we lose the very eventfulness that makes us unique, and that is difference, how our experiences shape who we are and how we rationalize things by way of the imagination.</p>

<p>The quote by Sepper awakens us to questions: if our responses are reactionary, we respond in the way of efficient causation; that is, we respond to their thoughts, and fall into the trap of using their logic.  But what if we responded by moving from the efficiency of a quick response, to one that is constructed, that includes how we think? What if we deconstructed the question, and introduced how we ourselves are envisioning or seeing the world? If what we are trying to reject is the logic behind the response, then our responses need to move away from a reactionary response to one that is reflectiive and creative.</p>

<p>As I reflect back on some of my teaching moments, I remember times when I have been more reactionary than reflective and creative with my students.  Maybe, if I am aware of my self, it was because of my insecurities, my own trying to form and shape what I think, that I may have given a reactive, inflamed response. As I try and do now, as I see the wisdom of my mentors and colleagues, my responses should be creative, asking the one asking the question to see their own logic, with its own presuppositions, to look at it from a different perspective, to see how perspecitves have the ability to be angled, shaped, to see in novel ways.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="thinking" /><category term="reactionary" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[thinking that is reactionary]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">alchemy as hieratic art, henry corbin</title><link href="https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2020/alchemy-as-hieratic-art-henry-corbin_ue9ork487eecchjz/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="alchemy as hieratic art, henry corbin" /><published>2020-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2020/alchemy-as-hieratic-art-henry-corbin_ue9ork487eecchjz</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2020/alchemy-as-hieratic-art-henry-corbin_ue9ork487eecchjz/"><![CDATA[<p>link: http://www.aaroncheak.com/alchemy-as-a-hieratic-art</p>

<p>I would like to thank Aaron Cheak for this wonderful translation from Henry Corbin.  The selections get to the heart of Corbin’s understanding of alchemy. It resonates with the process of concrescence in Alfred North Whitehead.  It breaks from any materialism and from any spiritualism.  It seeks what Roland Faber writes as the intermezzo, the in-between. It is wholistic, in each different, with resonances when we relate with one another.</p>

<p>A wonderful quote on defining/experiencing/participating in alchemy:</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>Not only does it contain a mine of information, it is eminently representative of a conception of alchemy that is neither a simple dramaturgy of the unconscious or psychological allegory, nor a simple manipulation of materials practiced in the manner of a mere chemist or pharmacist. It is an operation at once material and spiritual, the juncture between the two aspects remaining the hidden secret underneath the symbols of the “Philosophers” (as the alchemists designate themselves). And because the <em>ars hieratica</em> integrates the two operations, its locus is in fact a mesocosm (<em>intermonde</em>), of which the ritual form and the cadre of a temple are the best means of imposing the integral representation.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>#henrycorbin
#imagination
#alchemy
#process
#intermezzo
#rolandfaber
#alfrednorthwhitehead
#rafaelreyes</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="henrycorbin" /><category term="imagination" /><category term="alchemy" /><category term="process" /><category term="intermezzo" /><category term="rolandfaber" /><category term="alfrednorthwhitehead" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[quote on the alchemy]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">a selection from henry corbin’s _the jasmine of fedeli d’amore_</title><link href="https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2018/a-selection-from-henry-corbins-the-jasmine-of-fedeli-damore_ot7slkaok5pjmkj8/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a selection from henry corbin’s _the jasmine of fedeli d’amore_" /><published>2018-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2018/a-selection-from-henry-corbins-the-jasmine-of-fedeli-damore_ot7slkaok5pjmkj8</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2018/a-selection-from-henry-corbins-the-jasmine-of-fedeli-damore_ot7slkaok5pjmkj8/"><![CDATA[<p>I am in the middle of writing my chapter on Imagination and the space of multiplicity, when I found this wonderful piece of translation and interpretation by Corbin, and had to add it here for rememberance.  Here it goes:</p>

<h3 id="seek-me-in-the-mystical-abode-of-love-">“Seek Me in the Mystical Abode of Love “</h3>
<blockquote>
  <p>But, whoever dares to carry out this search will find himself obliged to defy the norms and forms of thought in the common, socialized forms of religion, and his proposals will sound like paradoxes (the <em>shath</em> of which Ruzbehan was so fond). To remain faithful, with absolute sincerity, to the presence of his ‘inner’ God, one may have to accept being taken for a ‘black sheep’ in the eyes of ‘right thinking’ Muslims. Such was the case with those called <em>maldmati</em> among whom we find Hafiz. Now, Ruzbehan tells us a detail about himself which really underlines his affinity with Hafiz. He mentions this on the occasion of one of his visions when the contradiction between the Unique and the Multiple was resolved for him; a contradiction that exoteric theology is powerless to overcome, since it recedes before it:</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>In the days of my youth, met a shaykh who was a man of great mystic science, a <em>maldmati</em> shaykh, whose true face was unperceived by the mass of mankind. One night, I was contemplating a vast plain in the plains of Mystery when suddenly, on the approaches to that plain, I saw God in the guise of that shaykh. As I came up to him, he made a sign to me, showing me another plain. I advanced towards this plain and I saw a similar shaykh and again the shaykh was God. He made another sign, showing me another plain, and so on, until he had disclosed seventy thousand plains to me, and each time a plain drew nearer, I saw a figure similar to the one I had seen first. I said to myself: And yet, God the Most High is unique, one, indivisible, transcending (<em>monazzah</em>) small or large numbers, along with equals, contraries and similars. Then I was told: such are the theophanies of the eternal Attributes, they are boundless. At that moment, I felt the gripping presence of the esoteric realities of tawhid from the sea of Magnificence.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>The meaning of this vision is perfectly clear. The plurality of limitless theophanies - a stumbling block for the naive consciousness which would simply see polytheism in it - is resolved each time into being the multiplication of unity by itself, the product of which is always and each time a unity, that is, the unity of the Contemplating and the Contemplated. Such is the visionary mode, a mode which enables the mystic to re-discover in the creature the secret of the Uncreated, without negative theology nor a dialectic of the inaccessible. Recounting another vision in which the whole series of divine Attributes corresponding to the human form were revealed to him, and having been admitted to take part in a mysterious divine Supper, Ruzbehan exclaims: “My God, you nevertheless transcend the act of eating and drinking. If the tears of repentance are the drink of Angels, what of the tears of desire and intimacy shed at the time of the Vision?” “And He said: ‘that is my drink.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>pp. 212-13, The Jasmine of Fedeli D’Amore, Henry Corbin</p>

<p>#henrycorbin #love #imaginal #imagination #multiplicity #beyondreligion #religion #whiteheadsrationalreligion #whiteheadsexpressivereligion</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="henrycorbin" /><category term="love" /><category term="imaginal" /><category term="imagination" /><category term="multiplicity" /><category term="beyondreligion" /><category term="religion" /><category term="whiteheadsrationalreligion" /><category term="whiteheadsexpressivereligion" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[quote on the imagination]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">beyond the bifurcation of imagination</title><link href="https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2018/beyond-the-bifurcation-of-imagination_s3puorj3sa77jdsh/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="beyond the bifurcation of imagination" /><published>2018-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2018/beyond-the-bifurcation-of-imagination_s3puorj3sa77jdsh</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2018/beyond-the-bifurcation-of-imagination_s3puorj3sa77jdsh/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="beyond-the-bifurcation-of-imagination">beyond the bifurcation of imagination</h1>

<p>Reading Amy Kind and Peter Kung’s magnificent edited work <em>Knowledge Through Imagination</em>, and am thinking through it’s implications.  For Kind/Kung, their goal in the text is to lift up the instructive implications of the imagination over and beyond the transcendent capabilities.</p>

<p>The problem with the transcendent capabilities of the imagination is its ability to disengage with the limitations of this worldly experience.  That is, there are no constraints in the transcendent imagination (fantasy).  This poses problems for both Kind/Kung because knowledge formation cannot find its derivation in the imagination.  Kind/Kung look to find compatibility within the two forms of imagination by turning the faculty of imagination into a constrained imagination, limited by the ideas and things that the self gives into it.  This allows for a focused thought for possibility in accessing new knowledge.</p>

<p>Although I am fond of it, and do not neglect it (I think this is necessary!), I see that what is missing is a relational approach to the imagination that is more known in the works of John Sallis, and hidden within Alfred North Whitehead’s work.  It is a relational imagination which blurs the boundary between transcendent and instructive, and allows for the connections of other actual occasions, entities, to dictate and develop knowledge.  For instance, Sallis calls for a form of gazing at a space, which is the entrance to the imagination, as gazing provides the space for in depth viewing of the entity down to the elementals, the most basic of all things.  And even then we are not seeing the origins, but rather the manifestations of the entity realized, the thing in itself.</p>

<p>Alfred North Whitehead offers a similar response in the concrescing of actual occasions, in which they become possibilities seeking a response.  Instead of beings, we are becomings, always in process, and thus always being introduced into possibilities.  Experiences therefore become important for our becoming, to be prehended and felt for a form of analysis towards satisfaction.  But in our becoming we are just possibilities waiting to become.  And when we become, we become actual, a datum for every other becoming.  This is the imaginative generalization of actual occasions Whitehead is trying to get at: we are imaginative becomings, not repetitions, but becoming new at each moment because we are not the exact same things pertaining to time and space.  The facts that we categorize are “bare facts” to Whitehead, and thus have a facticity because of the evaluation we give to it.  It becomes valuable.  And thus what we value is because of an imaginative undertaking of imaginative feeling, one that is not untrue, but is not yet fully realized.  This makes it both transcendent and instructive, as we have not yet been (becoming, transcendent), and yet is instructive for the future of the actual occasion as a datum for feeling (the superjective feeling of the actual occasion as actualized).  So for Whitehead imagination is integral for any becoming for without it, the act of becoming is mere repetition.</p>

<p>#AmyKind #PeterKung #JohnSallis #AlfredNorthWhitehead #imagination #repetition #actualoccasion #transcendentimagination #instructiveimagination #nonbifurcationofimagination</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[on focusing the imagination]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">glimpses of breakages</title><link href="https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2018/glimpses-of-breakages/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="glimpses of breakages" /><published>2018-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2018/glimpses-of-breakages</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.processimagining.com/blog/2018/glimpses-of-breakages/"><![CDATA[<p>As quiet as I am, as often times I may accept status quo, I’m anarchic.  I fight, inwardly, on how to break free, to respond to questions that some have said is not possible, too hard.  And in my own writing I am trying to break free from the move towards sciences as the best purveyor of what things are and how things are.</p>

<p>Now, don’t get me wrong, I enjoy science.  I benefit from the advances of science.  I even push for its advancement, albeit with some trepidation, some apprehension as to its fruits (Facebook social networking, the loss of private data, hacking, all come from the good and bad of technological advancements).  And yet, what concerns me is its sense of efficiency, which creeps into aspects in which it should not, due to its danger of cropping meaning and purpose.  Maybe our mistake of technology was to think of it in its pragmatic senses, making it utilitarian, and thus it creeps back upon us that purpose and meaning become utilitarian, pragmatic, and thus removing the manyness of, yes, opinion.</p>

<p>So I look for breakages.  Places where things are broken.  Cracks.  Because it is in those places where interest arises.  So in my readings for my work, I came across George Steiner’s book <em>Real Presences</em>, where (internally of course) I am screaming “yes!  this is it!”  In his first section Steiner looks at the limit of theory when moving into the field of hermeneutics, language, music.  To theorize means to place limits, to develop some measure so as to verify through experiment or predictive application its truthfulness (79,81).</p>

<p>But by what measure?  Who decides?  This is for Steiner the piece which breaks theory, which sets it at its limit as to its ability to enter into the aesthetic, which always breaks logic, or any measure as to its meaning.  Steiner writes,</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>But what measure?
The absolutely decisive failing occurs when such approaches seek to formalize <em>meaning</em>, when they proceed upward from the phonetic, the lexical and the grammatic to the semantic and aesthetic.  It is this progression which no analytical-linguistic technique, however systematic its trappings, however abstruse its aspirations, has ever taken convincingly…A sentence always means more. (81-82)</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This is a powerful realization, that theory is stopped in its tracks because it cannot leap the gap that imaginative inquiry can.  The theory which is held by an idea is held in place, because the idea is unable to envelope itself around anything in the space of the aesthetic.  I argue it is because the imaginative is meant to bring together that which cannot, while not affecting either in their determinateness.  There is just too much within the possibility of images and language to contain it within an idea or even a methodology that is universalizing.  There can be no science or theory to meaning because the finite aspects that we grasp produce limitless possibilities.  Steiner writes,</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>an object, the description of whose formal components can be finite, demands and produces infinite response…the manifold of possible meanings–and the category of the meaningful is too static when applied to the poetic–is the exponential product of all possible sense or non-sense worlds as these are construed, imaged, tested, indwelt through the interaction of two liberties: that of the text, in movement across time, and that of the receiver (83).</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The poetic, the image, the imagination, they each bring forth from intuition, and only from that emergence can there be any form of interaction with it.  The intuitive feeling and trace of the image, of writing, of music, of language, are to be experienced, and then only analyzed.  But truth is not what is to be sought, but meaning.  And meaning breaks smooth logic and truths, because meaning indicates that there is a life that is seeking its actualization (see Deleuze, <em>Pure Immanence</em>)</p>

<p>The poetic is important.  It forces a progression and a break; it introduces questions that force us to once again deconstruct and reconstruct our prior held notions.  But it is not meant to go against science itself, but to make both realize that each does not contain the fulness of the things in themselves. The imagination may allow for the emergence of things to come forth, but the sciences in all its fullness is important to line up possibilities of how it becomes.</p>

<p>Thus, my (inward, moving outward) anarchy is meant to reveal that no smooth lines really exist.  There are breakages, cracks in things, which bursts bubbles and breaks us out of the norm, to what is possible.  This can be done in sciences, or religion, in philosophy or anything else.  Our precision analytical capabilities cannot show us all of reality, but must be made to fit within it (see Alfred North Whitehead, <em>Aims of Education</em>)</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="foucault" /><category term="whithead" /><category term="process-thought" /><category term="anarchy" /><category term="steiner" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I look for breakages, places where things are broken, the cracks.]]></summary></entry></feed>