<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://pi.github.io/pi.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://pi.github.io/pi.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2023-06-17T23:51:04+00:00</updated><id>https://pi.github.io/pi.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Process Imagining</title><subtitle>Thoughts on religion and philosophy in process and post-structural perspective. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">quote, michael v. mcginnis, rewilding imagination</title><link href="https://pi.github.io/pi.github.io/blog/2023/quote-michael-v_kmt90aryyik6wvkc/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="quote, michael v. mcginnis, rewilding imagination" /><published>2023-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pi.github.io/pi.github.io/blog/2023/quote-michael-v_kmt90aryyik6wvkc</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pi.github.io/pi.github.io/blog/2023/quote-michael-v_kmt90aryyik6wvkc/"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>The problem is that industrial culture is based on a mode of mimesis that simulates itself over and over again. In our emerging global society, the human being stands in the middle of a “fun zone” with walls of mirrors, where one’s reflection is all-too- human. Something is behind these human images-a psychology that supports a mimesis that fails to recognize its origin, and, therefore, it downplays the sensuous life.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>#imagination</p>

<p>#creativeimagination</p>

<p>#induastrialsociety</p>

<p>#culture</p>

<p>#machinations</p>

<p>#sustainability</p>

<p>#nature</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="imagination" /><category term="creativeimagination" /><category term="induastrialsociety" /><category term="culture" /><category term="machinations" /><category term="sustainability" /><category term="nature" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[quote on the imagination]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">goethe and the imagination</title><link href="https://pi.github.io/pi.github.io/blog/2023/goethe-and-the-imagination_92q4bxj6xnw9o6r0/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="goethe and the imagination" /><published>2023-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pi.github.io/pi.github.io/blog/2023/goethe-and-the-imagination_92q4bxj6xnw9o6r0</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pi.github.io/pi.github.io/blog/2023/goethe-and-the-imagination_92q4bxj6xnw9o6r0/"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>“A man born and bred up to the so-called exact sciences does not find it easy to realize, perched as he is on the heights of his own rationality, that there might also exist an exactitude of the imagination working through the senses, without which art would be simply unthinkable” (Aphorismen und Fragmente, Werke, Zürich, 1952, 17, 779)</p>
</blockquote>

<p>#goethe</p>

<p>#imagination</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="imagination" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[quote on the imagination]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">hakim bey and the imagination</title><link href="https://pi.github.io/pi.github.io/blog/2022/hakim-bey-immediatism-8-9_aqwpjv3dnjjjoyal/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="hakim bey and the imagination" /><published>2022-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pi.github.io/pi.github.io/blog/2022/hakim-bey-immediatism-8-9_aqwpjv3dnjjjoyal</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pi.github.io/pi.github.io/blog/2022/hakim-bey-immediatism-8-9_aqwpjv3dnjjjoyal/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="hakim-bey-immediatism-8-9">hakim bey, immediatism, 8-9.</h1>

<blockquote>
  <p>Computers, video, radio, printing presses, synthesizers, fax machines, tape recorders, photocopiers - these things make good toys, but terrible addictions.</p>

  <p>Finally we realize we cannot “reach out &amp; touch someone” who is not present in the flesh. These media may be useful to our art - but they must not possess us, nor must they stand between, mediate, or separate us from our animal/animate selves. We want to control our media, not be controlled by them. And we should like to remember a certain psychic martial art which stresses  the realization that the body itself is the least mediated of all media.</p>
</blockquote>

<h1 id="hakim-bey-immediatism-7">hakim bey, immediatism, 7.</h1>

<blockquote>
  <p>For art, the intervention of Capital always signals a further degree of mediation. To say that art is commodified is to say that a mediation, or standing-inbetween, has occurred, &amp; that this betweenness  amounts to a split, &amp; that this split amounts to “alienation.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>#art</p>

<p>#creation</p>

<p>#imagination</p>

<p>#hakimbey</p>

<p>#technology</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="imagination" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[quote on the imagination]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">alchemy as hieratic art, henry corbin</title><link href="https://pi.github.io/pi.github.io/blog/2020/alchemy-as-hieratic-art-henry-corbin_ue9ork487eecchjz/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="alchemy as hieratic art, henry corbin" /><published>2020-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pi.github.io/pi.github.io/blog/2020/alchemy-as-hieratic-art-henry-corbin_ue9ork487eecchjz</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pi.github.io/pi.github.io/blog/2020/alchemy-as-hieratic-art-henry-corbin_ue9ork487eecchjz/"><![CDATA[<p>link: http://www.aaroncheak.com/alchemy-as-a-hieratic-art</p>

<p>I would like to thank Aaron Cheak for this wonderful translation from Henry Corbin.  The selections get to the heart of Corbin’s understanding of alchemy. It resonates with the process of concrescence in Alfred North Whitehead.  It breaks from any materialism and from any spiritualism.  It seeks what Roland Faber writes as the intermezzo, the in-between. It is wholistic, in each different, with resonances when we relate with one another.</p>

<p>A wonderful quote on defining/experiencing/participating in alchemy:</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>Not only does it contain a mine of information, it is eminently representative of a conception of alchemy that is neither a simple dramaturgy of the unconscious or psychological allegory, nor a simple manipulation of materials practiced in the manner of a mere chemist or pharmacist. It is an operation at once material and spiritual, the juncture between the two aspects remaining the hidden secret underneath the symbols of the “Philosophers” (as the alchemists designate themselves). And because the <em>ars hieratica</em> integrates the two operations, its locus is in fact a mesocosm (<em>intermonde</em>), of which the ritual form and the cadre of a temple are the best means of imposing the integral representation.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>#henrycorbin
#imagination
#alchemy
#process
#intermezzo
#rolandfaber
#alfrednorthwhitehead
#rafaelreyes</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="henrycorbin" /><category term="imagination" /><category term="alchemy" /><category term="process" /><category term="intermezzo" /><category term="rolandfaber" /><category term="alfrednorthwhitehead" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[quote on the alchemy]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">a selection from henry corbin’s _the jasmine of fedeli d’amore_</title><link href="https://pi.github.io/pi.github.io/blog/2018/a-selection-from-henry-corbins-the-jasmine-of-fedeli-damore_ot7slkaok5pjmkj8/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a selection from henry corbin’s _the jasmine of fedeli d’amore_" /><published>2018-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pi.github.io/pi.github.io/blog/2018/a-selection-from-henry-corbins-the-jasmine-of-fedeli-damore_ot7slkaok5pjmkj8</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pi.github.io/pi.github.io/blog/2018/a-selection-from-henry-corbins-the-jasmine-of-fedeli-damore_ot7slkaok5pjmkj8/"><![CDATA[<p>I am in the middle of writing my chapter on Imagination and the space of multiplicity, when I found this wonderful piece of translation and interpretation by Corbin, and had to add it here for rememberance.  Here it goes:</p>

<h3 id="seek-me-in-the-mystical-abode-of-love-">“Seek Me in the Mystical Abode of Love “</h3>
<blockquote>
  <p>But, whoever dares to carry out this search will find himself obliged to defy the norms and forms of thought in the common, socialized forms of religion, and his proposals will sound like paradoxes (the <em>shath</em> of which Ruzbehan was so fond). To remain faithful, with absolute sincerity, to the presence of his ‘inner’ God, one may have to accept being taken for a ‘black sheep’ in the eyes of ‘right thinking’ Muslims. Such was the case with those called <em>maldmati</em> among whom we find Hafiz. Now, Ruzbehan tells us a detail about himself which really underlines his affinity with Hafiz. He mentions this on the occasion of one of his visions when the contradiction between the Unique and the Multiple was resolved for him; a contradiction that exoteric theology is powerless to overcome, since it recedes before it:</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>In the days of my youth, met a shaykh who was a man of great mystic science, a <em>maldmati</em> shaykh, whose true face was unperceived by the mass of mankind. One night, I was contemplating a vast plain in the plains of Mystery when suddenly, on the approaches to that plain, I saw God in the guise of that shaykh. As I came up to him, he made a sign to me, showing me another plain. I advanced towards this plain and I saw a similar shaykh and again the shaykh was God. He made another sign, showing me another plain, and so on, until he had disclosed seventy thousand plains to me, and each time a plain drew nearer, I saw a figure similar to the one I had seen first. I said to myself: And yet, God the Most High is unique, one, indivisible, transcending (<em>monazzah</em>) small or large numbers, along with equals, contraries and similars. Then I was told: such are the theophanies of the eternal Attributes, they are boundless. At that moment, I felt the gripping presence of the esoteric realities of tawhid from the sea of Magnificence.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>The meaning of this vision is perfectly clear. The plurality of limitless theophanies - a stumbling block for the naive consciousness which would simply see polytheism in it - is resolved each time into being the multiplication of unity by itself, the product of which is always and each time a unity, that is, the unity of the Contemplating and the Contemplated. Such is the visionary mode, a mode which enables the mystic to re-discover in the creature the secret of the Uncreated, without negative theology nor a dialectic of the inaccessible. Recounting another vision in which the whole series of divine Attributes corresponding to the human form were revealed to him, and having been admitted to take part in a mysterious divine Supper, Ruzbehan exclaims: “My God, you nevertheless transcend the act of eating and drinking. If the tears of repentance are the drink of Angels, what of the tears of desire and intimacy shed at the time of the Vision?” “And He said: ‘that is my drink.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>pp. 212-13, The Jasmine of Fedeli D’Amore, Henry Corbin</p>

<p>#henrycorbin #love #imaginal #imagination #multiplicity #beyondreligion #religion #whiteheadsrationalreligion #whiteheadsexpressivereligion</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="henrycorbin" /><category term="love" /><category term="imaginal" /><category term="imagination" /><category term="multiplicity" /><category term="beyondreligion" /><category term="religion" /><category term="whiteheadsrationalreligion" /><category term="whiteheadsexpressivereligion" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[quote on the imagination]]></summary></entry></feed>